SOA 지난 이야기
Previously on Sons of Anarchy...
AFT한테 잡혔는데
지미한테 내가 불었다고 한대요
ATF has me. So they're gonna
tell Jimmy I was the rat.
안 그랬다고요
I didn't help.
무슨 일이든지 하겠다고 해
You gotta convince Jimmy
you'd do anything for the cause.
그 AFT년 죽이고
Kill that ATF bitch.
나도 어쩔 수 없어
Box you put me in,
you give me no choice.
니네 아버지가
널 잘못 키웠구나
I guess Da raised
a little Irish pussy.
Oh!
젠장
Shit.
저 여자 누구에요?
That woman... who is she?
아기가 숨 못 쉰다고 거짓말 한 년
She's the one who told
me her baby was choking.
다른 여자들이었다면
견디지 못했겠죠
That rape would have
destroyed most women.
무슨 일이 있었든간에
극복하셨잖아요
Whatever it is you think you
have to do, you're past it.
그게 내 의무니까
This is how I do my part.
- 어디 가신대요?
- 가만 있어
- Hey, where's she going?
- Stay here.
도망쳐야 할지도 모르니까
She may need to get out fast.
에디?
Eddy?
안돼
Oh, God.
총 내려놔
Put down the gun.
저 여자가 강간을 도왔나요?
Was she involved in the rape?
그렇게 됐다니 유감이군요
I'm sorry that that happened to you.
이젠 어떡하는데?
And now what happens?
가요
Go.
기회를 줄 테니까
I'm giving you a chance.
이봐
Hey.
뭐지?
What are you doing?
총 내려놔
You need to put down the gun.
약은 년
You are a smart bitch.
스탈 요원이다
This is Stahl.
젬마가 내 총을 뺏었다
Clay Morrow's old lady took my gun.
에드먼드는 문으로 도망쳤으나
Edmond ran for the door.
젬마가 등을 쏴서 죽었다
Gemma shot him in the
back with my weapon. He's dead.
성모마리아님
Mother Mary.
도움이 필요해요
I need a little help.
나 도망가야 해
I'm on the lam.
- 어디로 갈 거야?
- 몰라요
- Any idea where we're headed?
- No.
- 어머님은?
- FBI가 들이닥쳐서 도망왔어요
- Where's Gemma?
- Feds raided the house. I had to leave.
- 왜 그래?
= 어머님이
- What's the matter?
- It's Gemma.
조벨 딸 따라가셨는데
She followed Zobelle's daughter into...
태라?
Tara?
젬마가 에디를 죽였어
Gemma killed my Eddy.
눈에는 눈이다
Son for a son.
안돼!
No!
뭔가 잘못됐어
가 볼게요
Something's wrong.
I got to go.
아일랜드 놈이
손자를 납치했다
Irish took my grandson.
내 아들!
He took my son!
우유를 먹을 아이가 없네
내 사랑이 떠나갔네
새벽의 상징처럼
No milk today
My love has gone away
The bottle stands forlorn
우유병만 홀로 있네
우유를 먹을 아이가 없네
왜 이리 평소같은지
A symbol of the dawn
No milk today
It seems a common sight
지나가는 사람들은 이유를 모르네
But people passing by
Don't know the reason why...
우유를 먹을 아이가 없네
항상 그렇진 않았네
그들은 기뻐하고
No milk today
It wasn't always so
The company was gay
밤낮을 바꿔버리네
남은 것은
They'd turn night into day
But all that's left
어둡고 외로운 정원 딸린 집 뿐이네
Is a place dark and lonely
A terraced house
동네 구석에서 신전처럼 빛나네
In a mean street back of town
Becomes a shrine
너를 생각할 때
둘이 살고 둘이 죽네
When I think of you only
Just two up
Two down...
라로이한테 전화왔어요
Laroy called.
그놈 찾았대요
They found the guy.
그래
Okay.
티그랑 얘기했냐
You talk to Tig?
네
Yeah.
사모님은 로그 강 바깥쪽의
모텔에 데려다 드렸어요
They moved Gemma to a motel
outside Rogue River.
조직이 아는 곳이라서
Club-friendly.
티그랑 오리곤 애들이
돌봐드릴 겁니다
Look, Tig and the Oregon guys...
they'll take care of her.
괜찮을 거에요
She's gonna be okay.
아벨 일 말하지 마
I don't want her finding
out about Abel.
압니다
I know.
불알이 얘기는 했어요
Had to tell her about Sack.
신문에 죄다 나왔거든요
애 납치된 건 없었지만
That shit's been all over the papers,
but the kidnapping hasn't hit the news.
모르게 둘 수 있을 겁니다
We should be able to protect her from it.
어딨어?
Where is he?
어제 경찰이 집으로 보냈답니다
PD let 'em back
into the house yesterday.
데리러 가자고
Let's go get him.
그렇게 하세요
It's okay.
저는 여기서 청소할게요
I'll stay here, tidy up.
우유병이 새벽의 상징처럼 서있네
The bottle stands forlorn
A symbol of the dawn.
아기 방이요
Nursery.
여보세요
Hello.
젠장
Shit.
잭스
Jax.
재키 보이
Jackie boy.
일어나 인마
Come on, kid.
계속 저러고 있어요
He's been like
this since it happened.
어떡할지 모르겠다구요
I don't know what to do.
우리가 돌봐 줄거다
We'll take care of him.
아벨 정보를 얻었어
We got some info on Abel.
라로이가 카메론 목격자를 찾았대
Laroy found a guy who made
some I.D. for Cameron.
야, 재키 보이
Hey, Jackie boy.
가서 씻자
Come on, shower.
Come on.
얼른
Come on, kid.
힘들구나
Hold on, sweetheart.
사모님이요
Love on the line.
고맙구만
Thanks, Bobby.
- 내 사랑
- 자기야
- Hello, my love.
- Hey, baby.
괜찮아?
You doing all right?
응
Yeah.
지낼만 해?
Place okay?
구리지만 안전하다니까
It's a, it's a
shithole, but I'm safe.
불알이 오늘 묻을 거야?
Burying the prospect today?
오늘은 장례식이고 내일 묻어
Wake tonight, funeral tomorrow.
- 가야 하는데
- 알아
- I should be there.
- I know.
당신 보고 싶어
I miss you so much.
나도 당신 보고 싶어
I miss you, too.
우리가 노력할게
We'll figure this shit out, baby.
그래, 알아
Oh, yeah, I know that.
사랑해
I love you.
잭스 바꿔 줄래?
Can I talk to Jax?
방금 샤워한다고 들어갔어
He just, uh,
jumped in the shower.
그래
Okay.
아벨한테 뽀뽀 전해줘
Hey, kiss Abel for me.
사랑한다고
Tell my boys I love 'em.
물론이지
Absolutely.
또 전화하자
We'll talk later, right?
응
Yeah.
안녕
Bye.
영어자막 : by honeybunny
한글번역 : DC 기미갤 chuckymee@hotmail.com
Riding through this world All
alone God takes your soul
You're on your own
The crow flies straight
A perfect line
On the devil's bed
Until you die
Gotta look this life
In the eye.
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com
고마워
Thanks.
얘기 좀 하실래요?
Can I, can I talk
to you for a second?
그럼
Sure.
헤일 씨가 최대한 미뤄 줬지만
Hale pushed it back as
far as he could, but I have to
저 스탈 요원하고 FBI한테 증언 해야해요
talk to Stahl and the FBI
today, tell them what I saw.
그래
Okay.
잭스한테 뭐라고 말할지...
Well, I tried to
ask Jax what I should...
아는 대로 말해
As much of the truth as you can.
아벨을 얼른 찾아야지
We want everybody looking for Abel.
기본적인 거 말해 줘
Just give 'em the basics.
카메론은 FBI도 알아
아일랜드 인맥도
Feds know who Cameron
is, his real IRA ties.
우리 관련돼 있다는 것만 빼놓고 말해
All you got to do is leave
out the details about our association.
- 그 사실이 도움이 된다면...
- 도움 안 돼
- But if those details help find him...
- They won't.
카메론이 불알이를 죽이고 손자를 납치했다
스탈이 거짓말 하고
Cameron killed Sack, he took my
grandson 'cause Stahl lied and
젬마를 뒤집어 씌워서
framed Gemma.
이게 진실이야
That's the real truth.
이봐
Hey.
잘했어
철 들었구나
You've done good, sweetheart,
you really stepped up.
잭스가 널 가져서 다행이다
You're the best thing
that happened to Jax.
네가 있어서 다행이야
We're all so glad you're around.
같이 갈래?
Can you ride?
네
Yeah.
잠시만요
Give me a minute.
내 탓이라고 생각하지
I think you blame me.
너랑은 상관없잖아
This has nothing to do with you.
전혀
None of it does.
전혀?
None of it?
이렇게 돼서 유감이고
I'm sorry this happened.
난 그럴 자격도 없었어
I had no right asking you for this.
그게 뭔데?
Asking me for what?
내 곁에서
내 일부가 되어 달란 말
Wanting you to stay,
be part of what I am.
내 생각이 짧았어
I didn't think it through.
나야 원래 그런 놈이지만
Obviously, I do that.
I don't think shit through.
남에게는 아니잖아
What it might do to other people.
내가 남이니?
I'm not other people.
넌 시카고로 갔어야 했어
You should have
gone back to Chicago.
콘 요원 일이
The shit that happened with Kohn...
끝이었어야 했다고
that should have been the end.
못 알아듣겠어
You're not making sense.
끝내자
This has to be the end.
차밍을 떠나고
날 떠나
You got to get out.
From Charming. Away from me.
잭스, 그냥 그렇게...
Jax, you...
you can't just expect me to...
제발, 태라
Just... Tara...
복잡하게 하지 말자
Please don't complicate it, okay?
간단하잖아
It's simple.
넌 우리가 아냐
You don't belong here.
저 사람인가?
This the guy?
맞습니다
Yeah, that's him.
아는 대로 불어
Hey, tell him what you know.
찾으신다는 아일랜드 사람의
일을 제가 좀 해 준 거 같아요
Uh, I think I did some work for
the Irishman you're looking for.
- 이 놈?
- 네 맞아요
- - Is that him?
- Yeah, that's him.
- 무슨 일?
- 아일랜드 여권,
- - What kind of papers?
- Irish passport.
미국 여행비자,
American travel visa.
아예 뜨려고 했군
Means he's trying
to leave the country.
무슨 이름으로?
What name's he using?
"티모시 오델"요
Timothy O'Dell.
주소는 벨파스트
Belfast Address.
아기 여권은?
You do an ID for a baby?
아뇨, 혼자 왔던데요
No.
No, he came alone.
상관 없어
It don't mean nothing, brother.
아벨을 데리고 나가려면
아기 여권도 있어야 하잖아
If he still had Abel, he'd need a passport
to get him out of the country.
아직 국내에 있을 거야
Maybe Cameron's still local.
아벨 건 다른 데서 만들었겠지
Yeah, or maybe he went
someplace else for Abel's ID.
납치된 애라면
Someone trying to hide-hide
a kid, I mean, uh,
저도 안 해줬을 겁니다
휘말리기 싫다고요
he's not gonna get any papers from me.
I don't want that kind of trouble.
- 어디서 만났지?
- 차이나타운요
- Where'd you meet this guy?
- Chinatown.
- 배 타는 곳은 없나?
- 앨리스 가에요
- Any public marinas nearby?
- Alice Street.
친구한테 전화해서
티모시 오델이 배를 탔냐고 물어보죠
I'll call our friend, see
if a Timothy O'Dell's got a boat there.
고맙네 아저씨
Thanks, Mr. Magoo.
알겠습니다
All right. Okay.
사무실 옮긴다며
I hear you're moving offices.
응, 다음주 목요일부터 정식으로
Yeah.
It'll be official next Thursday.
잘됐다, 잘했어
That's good.
You deserve it.
고마워
Thanks.
- 왜 왔어 형?
- 힘든 한 주였지
- - So, what do you need, Jake?
- It's been a rough week.
응
Yeah.
조벨 일
That shit with Zobelle.
미안하다
I'm sorry.
Hmm?
상관없잖아
Doesn't matter now.
이제 인터폴 문제지
He's Interpol's problem.
웨스턴은 클레이 덕분에 죽었을 테고
Weston's dead, courtesy
of Clay, I'm sure.
차밍을 도울 수 있을 거라 생각했다
I saw an opportunity I
thought could help this town.
알아
Yeah, I know.
시장직 계획은 어떻게 돼 가?
So, how are the mayoral
plans shaping up?
나랑 오스왈드가 주 후보야
Well, it looks like it's
me and Oswald in the primary.
민주당 후보는 없고
No one on the Democratic ticket.
- 인종이 중요하지
- 이길 수 있어?
- - Primary is the race.
- Think you can beat him?
몰라
I don't know.
돈도 많고
He's got money.
인맥도 넓은 놈이라
Got a lot of relationships.
경찰 서장이 내 편이 돼 주라
I'm gonna need the Chief
of Police in my corner.
당연하지, 형
I'm with you, Jake.
고맙다 동생아
That's good to know, brother.
언서가 13번 배랬어요
Unser said it was slip 39.
여기서 지키고 있어
Nobody gets past here.
네
Right.
올 거냐?
You with us?
네
Yeah.
비었습니다
Empty.
뜯어 봐
Rip it up.
뭔가 있을 거야
Got to be something.
젠장
Shit.
- 사모님 뭐 하세요?
- 차 좀 빌리자
- - Hey. What the hell you doing?
- I got to borrow a ride.
- 무슨 소리에요?
- 니 트럭이야?
- What are you talking about?
- Is that your truck?
- 이러지 마세요
- 이거 놔!!
- Hey, you're not doing this.
- Let go of me!
- 미안해요
- 그래
- I'm sorry.
- Yeah.
나 집에 가야 해
Look, I...
I got to go home.
이런
Oh.
- 내가 필요할 거야
- 젠장
- He needs me.
- Shit.
지금 지명 수배 올라왔어요
APB went wide, sweetheart.
이 근처 5개주에서
사모님 얼굴을 안다고요
That means every cop in five
states knows your face.
들어가요
Come on.
현상금이 만 달러나 돼요
미안하지만 기다리세요
The Feds... they've offered ten K for
any info. We got to sit tight. Sorry.
영수증을 찾았는데
Found a receipt
from the Marina.
현금 결제라서
정보가 없네
Paid cash.
Couldn't find nothing else.
여기도
Yeah.
단서가 없어요
Needle's on empty.
배 탄 건 아닌듯 한데
He wasn't planning no sea voyage.
배는 망가뜨려 놔
Let's put this piece
of shit out of commission.
조용히
Quietly.
물론이죠
Absolutely.
저 검둥이들은 누구신가
Who are these fine dark fellows?
불안해 보이는데요
Looking nervous.
확인해 봐
Check it out.
정신 나갔구만
He's totally gone, man.
내가 가지
I got this.
가자
Here we go.
도망가 얼른!
Let's go! Let's go!
Move! Move! Move!
왜요?
What are you doing?
이 배 타고
도망 못 치게 해
Let's make sure he doesn't
take any more boat rides.
모자 주세요
Give me the hat.
애 찾으면 돌려 줄게
I'll give it back when I find him.
꼭 찾을 거다
Cause we are gonna find him.
알았어?
You hear me?
'Cause I can't stop Can't
stop now Turn your face around
Turn your face around
Listen up now, listen up now
Sick of working that 9 to 5
We fight to stay alive...
Now I'll take whatever's mine...
We gonna bring it to your house...
It's Mr. Chuck
You know I bring it fresh...
젠장
Oh, shit.
가요!
Go!
괜찮으니까
I'm all right.
괜찮다고
Go, man! I'm all right!
괜찮아
I'm all right.
Till we push 'em on the side,
man, oh, we gonna bring it
to your house...
고맙다
Thanks, brother.
So get on down and hit the ground
One, two, three, just hit the ground
We gonna bring
it to your house
So get on down and hit the ground
It's home invasion, baby,
one, two, three...
총 줘!
Get him a gun!
Smash him, he's...
Just hit the ground!
아 젠장
Oh, shit!
총 내려놔
내려놔!
Put your shit down!
Put it down!
내려놔!
Put 'em down!
- 놀러 온 거야
- 그래?
- Just a friendly visit, boys.
- Oh, yeah?
이 새끼는 왜 총 쏘려고 하는데?
Why'd this asshole try to
blow our heads off, then?
- 관심 끌려고
- 관심 주잖아!
- BOBBY Just trying to get your attention.
- Oh, well, you got it now, bitch!
관심 받았어요
I got his attention.
그렇네
I see that.
어쩔 거냐?
Now what?
부두에서 당신들 쫓은 거 아냐
We weren't after
you at the docks.
빨간 보트 말야
The red boat, the beater?
그거 주인 찾고 있는데
We're looking for the guy who owns it.
그거 우리 거야
We own that shit now.
예전 주인이
내 8개월짜리 아들을 납치했어
The guy that did own it,
he kidnapped my eight-month old son.
아일랜드 놈?
Irish dude?
그래
Yeah.
3일 전에 현금이 필요하다면서
Three days ago he
said he needed some quick cash.
부두에 배하고 총 가지고 왔더라고
Met him down at the docks
with the boat, some AKs.
근데 애는 안 데리고 왔던데
He told us where to find the car, but
he didn't have no kid with him, though.
그래, 고맙다
All right, hey, thanks.
아버지는?
So, how's the old man?
돌아가셨죠
Still dead.
그럴 수도 있지
You know, I hear that happens.
과부 헌팅하고 다니세요?
What are you doing,
cruising for widows?
불알이 묻을 데 찾아보고 있어
돌아다니기 피곤해서
No. Making arrangements for Half-Sack's
hole, and I'm tired of this run, so...
그래요
Yeah.
알아요
Yeah, I know.
나한테 할 얘기 있냐?
You, uh, you want to
bounce something off of me?
JT만큼은 아니지만
나도 경험이 많거든
I mean, I'm not as smart as J.T.,
but I've been known to have my moments.
괜찮아요
I'm good.
정신과 상담의나 신부님이 없고
Jax... we don't, uh, we
don't have shrinks or priests.
나한테 얘기하기 싫어도 괜찮아
You don't want to talk
to me, that's fine.
적어도 조직중
누군가한텐 얘기하고 풀래?
Are you gonna talk to somebody
in this club and work this shit out?
균형을 잡으려고 노력해 왔어요
I've been trying to find some
time to balance my...
가족과 조직을 위해
right thing for my family, club.
이번엔 잘되겠지 할 때마다
Every time I think maybe I'm
heading in the right direction...
더욱 더 깊은 수렁으로 빠져요
I end up in a place I never
even knew could feel this bad.
제가 뭘 잘못했나요?
What did I do, man?
너야 충성심 깊고 착해
Look, you're
loyal, and decent...
올바른 것을 사랑하고
you love the right things.
니 애비도 그랬어
That's who he was.
나도 그립다
And I miss him.
그립다고
I miss him.
카메론이 아이를 납치할 때
당신은 어디 있었습니까?
When Cameron grabbed
the baby, where were you?
불알... 킵 시체 옆에
앉아 있었어요
I... slid down
onto the floor next to Half-S...
Kip's body.
왜 아이를 납치했는지
말하지 않던가요?
He didn't say anything;
why he was taking the baby?
아들에 대한 복수? 몸값?
About his son being
killed, ransom?
안했다고 했잖아요
I told you, no.
작은 사실이라도 도움이 됩니다
The smallest
detail can help us.
아이 방에 절 묶어 놓고서
말없이 아벨을 데리고 갔어요
He forced me into the nursery, tied me up,
then left with Abel. He didn't say a word.
아무것도 모른다고요
I don't know anything else.
경찰에는 아직 아기 소식이 없어
The CHP, the sheriffs
got nothing new on the kid.
예감이 안 좋아, 미안하네
It's not looking good.
I'm sorry.
이름은 조회해 봤고?
Did you run the name?
샌 호아킨 명부에는
티모시 오델이 없어
No Timothy O'Dell
in the San Joaquin database.
- 최선을 다하고 있다
- 나도 알아
- I'm doing everything I can.
- I know you are.
마누라는 어때?
How's our girl doing?
- 잘 올려보냈어?
- 응, 괜찮아
- Tig get her up north okay?
- Yeah, she's fine.
마누라 얘기는 안 하는게 나을 거다
Probably best I don't give you
too many details.
안부 전해 줘, 알았지?
Tell her I would ask
about her, all right?
이봐
Hey. Hey!
가족이 심문받는 도중에
이러면 곤란하지
You ain't no use to your family
in a federal lockup.
잠시만요
Just give me a minute.
- 다시 한번만 물어볼게요
- 그렇게 하세요
- Let's see if she talks about him.
- It's okay. Great.
- 괜찮아?
- 네
- You okay?
- Yeah.
저도 괜찮습니다
I'm fine, too, thanks.
카메론을 만나보지 못했다는 말
믿기 힘들던데요
You know, I find it very hard
to believe that you never bumped
into Cameron Hayes
before the other day.
당신 시아버지와 총 거래한지
수 달이라구요
Been in town for months running
guns for your future father-in-law.
- 젬마에게 그런 짓을 하고
당신은 어떻게 공직을 지키죠?
- 그런 짓?
And I find it hard to
believe you've still got a badge
- after what you did to Gemma.
- What I did?
젬마가 들어와서 총을 쐈어요
Gemma came in guns blazing.
난 살아난 것도 기적이라구요
I barely escaped with my life.
역겨운 여자 같으니라구
You're a despicable woman.
남의 일에 끼어들지 말아요
Stay out of my business.
어쩔 건데, 의사 선생?
Or what, Doctor, hmm?
잭스 친구들 시켜서
날 쏘라고 할 건가?
Or you're gonna have one
of Jax's boys gun me down?
내 일은 내가 알아서 해
I don't need a
boy to handle my shit.
우리 가족한테서 떨어져
You stay away from my family.
젬마 씨가 잘 훈련시켜 놨군요
Well, Gemma trains 'em well.
I'll give her that.
젬마는 어딨죠?
Where is she, Clay?
몰라
No idea.
우리가 찾을 거에요
Well, we'll find her.
내 듣기로는 그럴 시간 없을 텐데
From what I hear, that's
not gonna matter much for you.
소장 말로는 당신이
FBI 코털을 건드렸다며
Chief tells me you really
pissed off the FBI;
3년간 쫓아 왔던 신나치 일을 뭉개고
stepping on a three-year
neo-Nazi sting.
나쁜 놈들이야 많죠
Lot of bad guys out there.
쫓다 보면 지저분해질 수도 있고
Sometimes the pursuit gets a little...
messy, you know?
조금 지저분해졌다고 당신 상관이
아일랜드 놈들 일을 뺏어갔나?
Is that why your bosses
pulled you off the Irish?
'Cause it got a little messy?
총알만 피했다고 다가 아닌 거야
Seems avoiding the bad shooting
hit didn't do you much good, after all.
젬마한테 일을 뒤집어씌워서
사람이 죽고 아이가 납치됐다
All you did by framing Gemma was get
a man killed and a baby kidnapped.
내 손자한테 일이라도 나면
Anything happens to my grandson,
내 약속컨데
네 머리부터
anything, I promise you...
I'm gonna shove a gun barrel
뒷구멍까지 총을 들이대고
썩은 심장을 날려 버릴 줄 알아
up that bony ass of yours and
I'm gonna blow your black heart out.
아 진짜
Jesus Christ.
좋아
All right.
아, 젠장
Aah, goddamn it!
타이밍 하고는
Oh! Really?
아야
Oh!
- 아 젠장
- 뭐야?
- Oh, shit!
- What the hell?!
- 내 차 훔치려는 거냐?
- 주차원이다 새끼야
- You stealing my car, bitch?
- No, I'm the valet, shithead!
죽을 줄 알아
I'll kill you.
사모님 미쳤어요?
Are you out of your goddamn mind?
그런가 보다
Yeah, maybe a little.
지쟈쓰
Jesus.
- 괜찮아요?
- 응
- You all right?
- I'm okay.
거시기 자를 뻔 했잖아요
Gemma, you almost
cut the guy's joint off.
자를 거였으면 깔끔하게 잘랐어
If I wanted him dickless,
it'd be laying on the ground next to him.
- 옆에 찌른거야
- 잘났네요
- It's a flesh wound.
- Oh, good.
조직에 또 무슨 문제가 되라고요
Well, that flesh wound's going
to cost this club a shitload of favors.
어차피 나 갈 건 알지?
You know you're not
going to be able to keep me here, right?
니가 어쩌든 갈 거라고
I'm going whether you like it or not.
사모님 저한테 왜 이러세요?
Gemma, why you
doing this to me? Why?
보스한테 사모님 지킨다고 약속 했어요
I promised Clay I would keep you safe.
그럼 날 따라오던지
Then you better
come with me, Tigger.
절개 시작합니다
Starting incision.
괜찮아요?
Are you all right?
저기...
이거 해 주세요
I need to...
Can you do this?
놀즈 선생?
Dr. Knowles?
- 내가 마저 치울게
- 됐어
- I'll finish up.
- I got it.
가 봐
You should go.
싫어
No.
콘한테서 도망가려고
차밍으로 온 거 아냐
I didn't come back to Charming
to run away from Cohn.
그 사람 죽여서
머무른 것도 아니고
And I didn't stay because
of what we did to him.
상관 없어
Doesn't matter now.
도나 죽었을 때, 니가 병원에서
When Donna was killed,
those things you said to me in
내 인생에 대해 말했었지
the hospital about my life being
a series of hit and runs...
내 모습만 보인다고
that my face was the
only one you saw...
괜히 그랬다
I shouldn't have said that shit.
진심이었잖아!
It was the truth!
겨우 진지하게 사나 했더니
I have created this very
serious life for myself.
실상은 내가 누군지도 모르겠고
And when I'm inside it,
I barely know myself.
수술을 하는데 가끔씩
I have these moments sometimes
in the middle of a surgery when
칼을 든 내 손이
suddenly I'm aware of my...
my hands, you know, doing these
내 손 같지 않아
extraordinary things.
이거 누구 손이지?
And I think, "Whose hands are these?
여기서 뭐 하는 거야?
What am I... what
am I doing here?"
하지만 너와 함께일 땐
그렇지 않단 말야
When I'm with you, I
never ask that question.
내가 정답이 아냐
I'm not the answer.
날 봐
이걸 보라고
Look at me.
Look at this.
항상 너만 보잖아
I am always looking at it.
항상 생각해 "내가 왜 여기에 있지?"
My brain never stops.
"Why am I here?"
여기에 있어야 하나?
You know, should I be here?
머무는 게, 떠나는 게?
엄마가 되는 게 두려운가?
Am I afraid to stay, afraid
to go, afraid to be a mother?
진짜 끝이 없어
미칠 거 같아
Shit, it's endless.
I drive myself crazy.
상관 없다고
None of that matters.
알아
I know.
그런 고민이 상관 없다는 건
나도 잘 안다고
That's become so clear to me.
The noise doesn't matter.
사람 사이에 없는 사람은
자신이 누군지 몰라
We don't know who we are until
we're connected to someone else.
사랑하는 사람과 있어야
더 좋은 사람이 된다고
We're just...better human beings when we're
with the person we're supposed to be with.
난 떠나면 안 돼
I wasn't supposed to leave.
여기 있어야 해
I belong here.
사모님, 전화하고 올 걸 그랬어요
Hey, Gem, you know, maybe we
should have called first.
아냐
어차피 안 받아
Nah.
He never answers the phone.
하는 일이 그렇지
That was her job.
가자
Come on.
볼 일 있으세요?
Can I help you?
그 새끼들이면
잡지 안 산다고 해
If it's those colored boys
again, you tell 'em
we don't need any more magazines.
목사님한테 잡지 팔러 온 거
아니라고 해 주세요
Just tell the reverend
I'm not here to sell him any magazines.
딸입니다
I'm his daughter.
죄송해요, 연락을 못 받아서
Sorry. I didn't know
you were coming by.
젬마예요
Gemma.
저는 티그고요
I'm Tig.
아멜리아에요
Amelia.
수간호사죠
I'm his caregiver.
6개월 전에 어머님께서 고용했어요
Your mom hired me about six months ago
when she couldn't handle him anymore.
여기서 살고요
I live in.
그렇게 심각해졌나요
I didn't know he got that bad.
괜찮으세요?
How's he doing?
때에 따라 달라요
Depends.
가끔은 저보다도 똑 부러지는데
Some days he's sharper than me.
보통은 여기가 어딘지도 모르죠
Others he barely knows where he is.
엄마 죽은 건 알아요?
Does he know Rose died?
교회 사람들이 말하려고는 했는데
Some folks from the church
came by, tried to tell him.
치매에 충격은 좋지 않아서요
But trauma like that, it usually
sends them deeper into the dementia.
모르는 게 나아요
It's probably for the best.
여기 씻을 데 없어요?
Excuse me, you got
a place I can wash up?
있죠
- Sure, yeah.
- Yeah?
이쪽이에요
Just this way.
안녕 아빠
Hi, Daddy.
나 젬마야
It's Gemma.
오 이런!
Oh, my... my God!
내 강아지!
I... My baby girl!
맞아
Yeah.
내 강아지
My baby girl!
나야
It's me. It's me.
니 엄마가 널 보면
얼마나 좋아할까
Your... your mama's gonna
be so glad to see you.
로즈? 로즈!
Rose? Rose?
로지!
Rosie?!
어딨어 여보?
Where are you, sweetie?
누가 왔는지 봐봐
You'll never guess who's here.
로지?
Rosie?
니 엄만 아마 미용실 갔을 거다
Oh, she's... probably...she's probably
down at Potenta's getting her hair done.
네
Yeah.
- 앉자
- 알았어요
- Sit with me.
- Okay, Daddy.
앉으세요
Come on, daddy. Here. Sit.
곧 올 거야
Yeah. Yeah, she'll be back soon.
퍽이나요
I hope not.
이리 와
Come here.
보스 안녕하세요
Mr.
President, good to see you.
진짜 안 됐지
Uh-huh, such a shame.
Yeah.
웃기지도 않아
It's unbelievable.
교황이 죽어도 이렇게는 안 한다
Archbishop Dome didn't get this
kind of turnout when he passed.
SOA가 타격받으면
사람들이 동요하지
Makes folks a little nervous
when they see SAMCRO vulnerable.
차밍 사람들이 그러면 안되는데
It's not supposed to happen
to them in Charming.
동요할 걸
Well, they should get nervous.
저 깡패들의 본모습을 보면 말야
See these scumbags for
what they rely are.
- 와 줘서 고마워
- 응
- Thanks for coming down.
- Yeah.
불알이 일은 유감이네요
Sorry about the prospect.
맘에 들던데
I liked that little guy.
코직한테 새 사람이
필요하다고 하던 참이었어
I was just telling Kozik
that we need bodies around our table.
일이 좆같아서
머릿수도 못 늘리고 있었잖아
We're so deep in our shit,
forgetting to grow club ranks.
예비 조직원 3명 있대요
Got three hang-arounds
we can bring up.
필구라, 셰퍼드, 마일즈
Filthy-Phil, Shepard and Miles.
좋아
Good.
해피도 자유 멤버 빠진다는데
Happy's tired of nomading.
북쪽보다 여기가 낫대요
He'd rather land here than up north.
해피가 오면 좋지
Happy's a welcome addition.
말해 봐
Tell them.
타코마 인원이 많아서요
Tacoma's growing
a little thick.
작은 곳으로 옮길까 하는데
I was hoping to jump
to a smaller charter.
차밍으로 돌아온다고?
You thinking about
coming back to Charming?
다음 주말에 신청 하려고요
Yeah, gonna put in a
request to transfer next church.
티그한테 물어봐야 되는데
That in's on Tig, brother.
될 거다
We'll make it happen.
가 봐
All right, man.
받을 거에요?
We will?
이라크 지뢰밭에서 살아남아
결국엔 부엌 바닥에서 죽는군
Made it through Iraqi minefields,
only to get taken out in a goddamn kitchen.
괜찮냐?
How you holding up, son?
네
I'm okay.
엄마랑 얘기하셨어요?
You talk to Mom?
응, 오늘 아침에
Yeah, this morning.
괜찮대
She's good.
가족 걱정 뿐이지
Worried about her family.
아벨 일은 몰라
She doesn't know about Abel.
자기 책임이라고 생각할 거야
She'd...
take it on, make it her burden.
도움 안 될 테니까
That wouldn't be helping anybody.
말 되네요
Makes sense.
너한테도 그래
Makes sense for you, too.
수많은 경찰들이
우릴 주시하고 있어
Probably 40, 50 patches
watching us right now.
우리가 이 조직의 과거이자 현재, 미래다
We represent the past, present
and future of this club.
우리야 민주적인 조직이지만
Sure, the Sons are
a democratic organization,
차밍에 우리가 있기에
but everybody knows
what happens in Charming
차밍이 그만큼 중요한 거야
sets the tone for every charter.
차밍이 어떻게 되는데요?
And what's happening in Charming?
네가 알잖냐
You tell me.
조직원들은 널 사랑해
These men behind us, they love you.
널 존경하고 네 슬픔을 이해한다
They respect you and they
understand your grief.
네가 그걸 어떻게
극복하는지도 볼 거야
But they're also wondering
what you're gonna do with it.
- 그건 제 일이잖아요
- 아니야
- That's my business.
- No, it isn't.
네 아버지한테 일어났던 일은
저놈들은 기억 못 해
None of these guys are old enough
to remember what happened to your old man.
토마스가 죽자
무너져 버렸던 것 말이다
How he... fell apart, lost
focus when Thomas died.
- 전 아버지와는 달라요
- 난 알지만 쟤들은 몰라
- Yeah, well, I'm not my old man.
- I know that, but they don't.
그러니까 니가 보여줘
You gotta show 'em something.
선택을 하란 말이야
Make the hard choice, son.
무슨 선택을요?
And what choice would that be?
아벨이 죽었다면 복수를 하고
Either Abel is dead,
and you want revenge,
살아 있다면
살인을 해서라도 찾아내
or he's alive, and you
would kill to find him.
그 선택마저 못 하겠다면
무릎이라도 꿇고 빌던지
Now if you can't make that
decision, then you better get
down on your hands and knees
and pray for something to get you there...
빨리
Fast.
사막의 한가운데
죽은 군인이 누워있네
Out in the desert there's
a soldier laying dead
독수리들이 그 눈알을 뽑아먹네
Vultures pecking the eyes
out of his head
저 시체가 나였을 수도 있네
Another day, that could
have been me there instead
아무도 날 사랑하지 않네
Nobody loves me here
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
Dad's gonna kill me
지뢰를 밟은 너는 고깃덩어리
You hit that booby trap and
you're in pieces With every bullet
쏟아지는 총알 위로 목숨이 오가네
With every bullet
your risk increases
알리바바는 우리와 다르네
Old Ali Baba he's a different species
아무도 날 사랑하지 않네
Nobody loves me here
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
Dad's gonna kill me
Dad's gonna kill me...
- 세상에!
- 모, 얘기 좀 할까?
- Mother of Christ!
- Mo, can I talk to you?
- 캐미, 여기서 뭐 해?
- 제발, 모린
- Cammy, what are you doing here?
- Please, Maureen?
누가 보기 전에 들어와
아이 때문인 거 명심해
Get in...quick, before anybody
sees you. Get that child out of the damp.
난 험비 안의 죽은 시체
I'm dead meat in my Humvee Frankenstein
난간에는 부딪쳐도
지뢰는 밟지 않네
I hit the roadblock
Somehow I never hit the mine
운이 좋아
주사위를 잘 굴렸을 뿐
The dice rolled
and I got lucky this time
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
And Dad's gonna kill me...
Dad's gonna kill me...
임신한 아내와
자식 하나
Got a wife and kid,
another on the way
오늘 죽지 않으면
집에 갈지도 모르지
I might get home
if I can live through today
예전에는 기도한 적도 없었네
Before I came out here
I never used to pray
아무도 날 사랑하지 않네
Nobody loves me here
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
And Dad's gonna kill me
아버지가 우울해하네
Dad's in a bad mood
Dad's got the blues
다른 사람의 짓
내 탓은 아니네
It's someone else's mess
that I didn't choose
아무도 날 사랑하지 않네
Nobody loves me here
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
Dad's gonna kill me...
가! 얼른!
Go, go, go!
새벽 순찰반이 귀환하지 않았네
Dawn patrol went out
and didn't come back
맥, 가르쳐 준 대로
전선을 걸고 기도해
Hug the wire
and pray like I told you, Mac
안 그러면 너도 고깃덩어리가 된다
Or they'll be shoveling
bits of you into a sack
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
and Dad's gonna kill me
젠장!
Oh, shit!
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
Dad's... gonna kill me
오 이런
Oh, God...
내 아이가!
That's my baby boy!
이럴 수가
Oh, my God!
누가 좀 도와 주세요
He's hurt! Somebody get help!
- 살려주세요
- 움직이지 마!
- Somebody get...
- Don't move!
도와줘요!
Help me!
죽게 두지 말아요
Tell me he's gonna be okay.
아가야
My baby! Oh!
아버지가 날 죽일 거야
Dad's gonna kill me
Dad's gonna kill me!
제발!
Please...!
오늘도 천사가 하나 늘었네
Another angel got
his wings this week
하얗게 재가 된 채로
Charbroiled with his own
Willie Pete
거짓말을 하면
아무도 죽지 않네
No one's dying
if you speak double-speak
잭스
Jax...
아버지가 날 죽이네
Dad's gonna kill me
Dad's...gonna kill me!
영어자막 : by honeybunny
한글번역 : DC 기미갤 chuckymee@hotmail.com
Sync & corrected by honeybunny
www.addic7ed.com